Henry Eklind

henry@karlek.io github.com/karlek +4673 783 96 15

Developer skills

I write safe code in any language and I prefer the most suited language for each task. However, I am especially adept in Go and I have followed its progression since 2012.

During my free time I usually write code for fun and I have written a few projects, for example:

- · the Markdown to HTML micro-service for our student chapters web page,
- · co-authored a flac audio decoding library for the Go community,
- · lots of 3D-visualization programs for recreational renders of fractals,
- · the backend infrastructure for a cloud-based, deep learning powered, image analysis project.

Work Experience

2016 — 2020 Tink AB

Backend developer

I reverse engineer bank application APIs for interoperability and write Java implementations of the APIs for our backend.

2015 Protracer

3D-software developer

During my time at Protracer (now known as Toptracer) I developed a visualization tool for plotting golf shots in 3D. The tool is used to track down bugs more intuitively.

2012 — 2014 Bitsec AB & eLär Sverige AB

IT security consultant

Worked with IT-security as a consultant where the tasks consisted of penetration testing and IT-forensics. Developed safe software for an IT related tool used in police raids.

Education

$2013-Present\ KTH$ - The Royal Institute of Technology

M.Sc. in Computer Science

A combined bachelor's and master's education in Computer Science. My master is specialized in machine learning and data science.

Spring 2018 Tohoku University, Japan

Kato-Nishiyama Laboratory - Research semester

Researched the viability and benefits of applying deep reinforcement learning in network control systems for more performant network routing.